For the last two questions,
对于最后两个问题
regarding which variables are related to salary?
哪些特征与工资和工作满意度相关
Each of these questions will involve not only building some sort of predictive model,
这两个问题 不仅是建立某种类型的预测模型
but also finding an interpreting the influential components of whatever model we built.
还包括找到对模型影响因素的解释
To get started, let's read in
先导入必要的库
the necessary libraries and take a look at some of the columns of interest.
然后观察一下感兴趣的一些列
So here are our libraries,
这里是我们导入的库
you'll notice that we have NumPy and Pandas which we've already been using a lot.
你应该能够注意到 我们一直都在用的 NumPy 和 Pandas
And then we have two libraries specific to
然后还有两个专门绘制可视化的库
visualizations and those are matplotlib and seaborn,
Matplotlib 和 seaborn
and then we also have this matplotlib inline to
后面还有 %matplotlib inline 来确保
make sure that our plots render within our notebooks.
绘制图表展示在 Notebook 里面
And then up here, these top three lines are basically used to build our predictive model.
这里的三行代码其实都跟构建预测模型相关
So, there's this train test split,
这个 train_test_split
which will split our data into training and test so that we can assure that
会将我们的数据集划分为训练集和测试集
whatever model we build on our training set will actually extend well into our test data.
确保训练集上建立的模型 可以很好地扩展到测试集
And then this metrics portion,
这里的指标部分
these are some pretty common metrics to use with any sort of
可以与任何类型的连续型目标变量
continuous response variable are the r2_score and the mean squared error.
一起使用的非常常见的指标 R 平方值和均方误差
And then, right now I'm just using a simple linear model but
在这里 我只是使用了简单的线性回归模型
there are lots of other predictive models that you could choose to fit to your data.
其实有很多其他的模型可以用来训练数据
And, depending on your background with machine learning,
取决于对机器学习的了解程度
you might be really comfortable.
你可能对这里的内容非常熟悉
With some of those, you'll be diving into the depths
我们在后续课程中还会继续深入 讲解相关的工作原理
So, if we read in the data,
在这里读入数据
we can take a quick look at the head of the data and what it looks
快速地浏览一下前五行数据
like this is what you have already seen in a lot of the other videos.
在前面的视频中 你也已经看到过很多次这样的操作了
We can also get a quick look at the continuous variables so you can see,
我们也可以浏览一下连续型数值变量的情况
these are the variables that are considered continuous in the data set.
这里看到的就是数据中的连续变量了
And here's like, a quick rundown of basically the max the 75th percentile 50,
里面的值主要是一些统计变量 比如最大值、第三四分位数、中位数、
25th, the min, the standard deviation I mean.
第一四分位数、最小值、标准差、均值等
And then this count is really useful,
这里的计数非常有用
because it can show us how many of those values are actually missing in our data set.
因为其可以展示每个特征缺失值的情况
So, you can see that there's only 12,891 individuals to post the salary, and,
你可以看到 只有 12891 个人发布了自己的工资
they're also missing points in all of these two but,
这些特征也有缺失值存在
because the total number of respondents looks to be
因为答卷者总数似乎在 51000 左右
this 51,000 and we could get a quick look at that too.
快速地来看一下
Yeah. So, 51,392 is the number of respondents.
是的 的确有 51392 个答卷者
So, any column that doesn't have that many appear,
也就是说 任何一个没有这么多计数的列
essentially has some missing data in it.
都包含了缺失值
So, one of the easiest ways to get a look at some of
一种很快捷的查看这些变量的方法
these variables is also to build Instagram is like
就是绘制直方图
a really useful thing to do and I frequently
非常方便 我会在后面加上分号
put a semicolon to get rid of a lot of those gross things,
这样就不会出现多余的文字了
but here you can sort of see,
这里你可以看到
each respondent only shows up once so that's why,
每个回答都出现了一次
it's got this gross looking plot.
所以这个图表看上去很不一样
But you can also see like,
不过你也可以看到
this is a left skewed distribution,
工作满意度以及对 Stack Overflow 的满意度都是左偏的
a right skewed distribution around salary,
工资是右偏的
a right skewed distribution around hours per week worked,
周工作时长和期望工资也是右偏的
and expected salary, and another left skewed distribution around career satisfaction.
职业满意度则是左偏的
So, it looks like these people are pretty happy with their jobs and
看上去 这些人对自己工作和职业都是比较满意的
their careers and somehow avoid working a lot.
而且不怎么过度加班
So, that's one way that we could look at the data.
这是一种观察数据的方式
Another really cool plot that I frequently make when
另一种我自己经常在分析前期用的图表
starting out these analysis is, a heatmap.
就是热图
So, if we look at,
我们来看一下
so this S and S is the seaborn library,
这里的 sns 就是指 seaborn 库
and it has a built-in heatmap.
其中有内置的热图函数
And if you pass in a correlation matrix,
如果你传入一个相关系数矩阵
so you can get that by just running the core method on your dataframe.
其实就可以画出图表了
And, I'm going to add an annotation,
但是 我要再传入标签
so that it passes in the numbers.
以及要求的小数位数
And then, this is basically just going to format my values to be only two decimal places.
也就是让相关系数都保留两位小数
So, here this doesn't only and again I kind of put in a semicolon at the end of the this,
然后在代码后面加上一个分号
so that I don't get that first part.
这样就不会返回第一行的文字
But this gives you a correlation matrix
这会绘制出 显示数据中所有数值变量之间相关系数的矩阵
One of the first things that I try to do is,
然后我还会做的事情是
just create the dataframe of all of
创建一个 DataFrame 其中包含所有用来预测目标变量的特征
the other thing that I want is just to poll the variable that I'm trying to predict.
然后单独提取出需要进行预测的变量
So in this case,
在这里 就是 Salary 列
Because its variable I'm trying to predict and I want to give
因为我们要预测的就是工资
a list of all the column names that I'm going to use to try to predict the response.
然后把所有用来预测目标变量的特征放在这个列表里
So, to begin with,
我们可以放入上面看到的所有数值变量
So that's the career satisfaction,
比如职业满意度
so basically any of these.
但是不用传入答卷者编号
that doesn't actually mean anything to me.
因为这对分析没有意义
So, job satisfaction, hours per week and stack overflow satisfaction.
然后是 工作满意度、周工作时长、对 Stack Overflow 的满意度
It's also the case that in the built-in scikit-learn models,
scikit-learn 内置模型中也是如此
you have the ability to pass an intercept by
默认情况下你还可以传入截距
default so you don't have to store it into the X matrix here,
所以并不需要将其存入 X 矩阵
it's just an argument that you can pass to any of the models
这只是一个参数 可以传入到任何 scikit-learn 的模型中
So, I'm not going to worry about that.
我不会为此担心
And then, essentially, the next thing that I like to
接下来 我要做的是把数据分成训练集和测试集
The way that this works is,
代码是这样写的
and I usually have to look at the documentation for this.
我自己经常需要查看文档才能确定正确的写法
Essentially, we can run this train test split which we read
基本上就是用上面导入的 train_test_split
in up above and pass it our X Matrix and the response.
传入 X 矩阵和目标向量
And then we pass pass a test size and a lot of times,
然后传入一个 test_size 控制测试集占比
you can pass it like a random state.
很多时候还可以传入 random_state 随机种子
So, we do a random in the number 42 that's the answer to everything in the world.
我们使用随机种子 42 这是很常见的选择
So, here you can see,
可以看到
what this is doing is it takes the x matrix that we just
这个函数需要传入这个 X 矩阵
created up here which is basically all the variables that we want to use to predict.
也就是刚才创建的 包含了所有的预测变量
It takes the response which is this variable
还传入了这里创建的目标变量
here and it's going to split these into two separate sets.
函数会将这些数据划分为两个单独的数据集
So, it's going to randomly split this.
使用随机方式划分 X
So, that parts of it go into the training and parts of it go into the test,
部分划分到 X_train 部分划分到 X_test
and it's going to randomly split this,
使用随机方式划分 y
so that parts of it going into the training and parts of it go into the test,
部分划分到 y_train 部分划分到 y_test
and the parts that go into the y test will match the parts that go into the X test.
但是划分到 y_test 和划分到 X_test 的数据是相对应的
And the parts that go into the y train,
划分到 y_train 和划分到 X_train 的数据也是相对应的
And this basically says, we want our test size to be
这个参数的意思是 我们想要的
30 percent of the original rows in these datasets.
测试集大小是原始数据集的 30%
And, the random state is a useful thing to set
设置随机种子也很有必要
just in case you decide to pass this dataset to someone else,
如果你想要分享代码和数据给其他人
and you want them to be able to get the exact same split of the data as you used.
会想要他们也能使用和你一样的数据划分
Whereas, if you don't set the random state,
如果没有设置随机种子
the rows that they end up with in their training and
那么他们得到的训练集和测试集
test could be completely different than the rows that you got.
都会与你不同
Then the next thing, that we'll want to do is just
接下来我们需要做的
instantiate our linear regression model.
是实例化线性回归模型
The way that we fit any supervised learning model is you first instantiate.
拟合任何监督学习模型的第一步都是实例化模型
So, you first instantiate your model,
所以首先来实例化模型
you then fit the model to the training data.
接着用该模型拟合训练数据
Then you predict on some test data
再用一些测试数据做预测
and then you frequently will score your model on the test.
最后通常需要对模型作出评分
That is, you compare what you
也就是 将预测结果和测试集中已知的实际结果做对比
And then that score,
最终得到的评分
is a way to compare your predictions from one model to the next model.
能够帮助你在不同模型之间进行比较
Okay. So, this is my usual go through and so the first thing that we want to do,
这大概就是我通常构建模型的流程
is just this instantiate step.
第一件事是实例化模型
So, I'm just going to instantiate my linear model
这里就是实例化我的线性模型
and we can do that with what you saw before.
就像你之前看到过的方式完成操作
Another really important thing,
另一个很重要的事情
is anytime you are working with
建模的时候
these models is you frequently want to normalize the data somehow.
通常都需要以某种方式对数据进行标准化
So, it doesn't matter if you're building neural networks or you're
不管是建立神经网络模型
building any supervised learning model and actually a lot of unsupervised models,
或是监督学习模型 以及很多的非监督学习模型
this is true too, but you want to standardize or normalize your data.
你都需要标准化你的数据
It's just a safe thing to do with almost any linear model.
尤其是线性模型
The only downside to this,
唯一的缺点就是
is that it can lead to a reduction in your interpretation of the features,
这会使特征变得没那么容易解读
but I think that's like far outweighed in terms of
但是我认为解读数据集差异的重要性
just the ability of these models to pick up
其实要远远高于
on what differences actually matter in your dataset.
对数据特征的解读
Then the next thing is, we should fit the model.
接下来要开始拟合模型了
Let's just do this,
就是这样做
so we can take a look.
我们可以先来看一下
So, if we look at X head,
X 的前 5 行数据
you can see that it has split our dataset and we have only those columns that we
可以看到数据集已经被拆分过了 只有指定的那些列
specified and it has all of them whereas if we look at like X train head.
包含了所有指定的列 如果我们看一下 X_train
You'll notice that the top rows aren't index the same way and if we do the test set,
你会发现前面几行的索引与之前不同 看一下 X_test
will have a completely different set.
也是完全不一样的
And, if we look at the shape of those things,
如果来看一下这几个数据集的 shape
you'll notice that there are 15,000 rows in the test.
可以看到测试集中有 15418 行
And if we look at the training set,
再来看一下训练集
you'll notice that there are almost 36,000 close to in the training set.
有 35974 行
So, it's a much larger set and the same as sort of true of the y train and y test,
训练集比测试集大很多 对于 y_train 和 y_test 也是一样
so free do this.
我们来试一下
So, the y train has the exact same number of rows but it's only a single column.
可以看到 y_train 的样本数跟 X_train 是一样的 只不过它只有一列
It's only one column and we can do the same thing with a test set,
再来看下 y_test
so you can see it's just the column and that
它也只有一列
those indices will match across the training and the test set.
索引都是相匹配的 y_train 与 X_train、y_test 与 X_test
Okay. So now that we have that,
好了 完成这一步
let's go ahead and try to fit our model,
可以开始拟合模型了
and you'll notice we fit this on the training data.
用我们的训练数据
So, I should be passing this X train and y train.
传入 X_train 和 y_train
Right. And, that's it. Yeah. And it's in that order.
搞定 就是这样的顺序
We can also check the docs and on this stuff,
不过我们也可以再来看一下文档
so I frequently will either work with code that I've written
我通常会对照自己以前写过的代码
before or I'm regularly checking the scikit-learn docs.
或者查看 scikit-learn 文档
You can always just run a question mark too. To see.
你也可以直接在函数后面打个问号查看文档
Right. So, that lm_model.fit should take an X and y,
就是这样 lm_model.fit 函数需要传入参数 X 和 y
and then some sort of sample weight,
然后还有这个 sample_weight
and then it tells you like what those things are,
接下来就是每个参数的具体说明
so it can be useful.
很有帮助
So, it looks like this, looks like when I try to run that I get an error.
运行代码出现了报错
So, this is where we're going to stop for
不过这节课就先讲到这里
this video and you're going to be doing some of this on your own,
你应该自己过一遍这些步骤
just to see what you think might have happened.
然后看你的代码中会发生什么